The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal\NSubtitles by Bonobosubs\Nhttps://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
There are so many mortals here,
they should be brimming with life.
So why is this death aura so prevalent ?
For a year,
I travelled through many cities all over Xue Yue.
There are no royal families here.
Instead,
every city belongs to a powerful cultivator.
Here,
the mortals are slaves.
The only meaning to their life
is to carve ice sculptures for cultivators
in order to make a living.
Thank you Immortal !
Mortals should have life energy,
but this death aura is particularly deep...
I don't like this place
but I believe I can gain a better understanding of Death here.
The ice sculptures of Xue Yue are very special.
The mortals carve the ice,
then a cultivator will place a formation on it
and use a secret technique.
The ice sculpture then comes to life and turns into a puppet.
This method is very mysterious...
I have been studying it for a long time
but I haven't learned anything yet.
My guess is
the ice sculptures are the foundation of Xue Yue.
If I can learn this method
and use it on wood carvings,
it will be very beneficial to me.
Xue Yue's defense has become weak
since the remnants of the Four Sect Alliance have been active.
Even if the Elders are not present,
these disorganized groups that fled the country won't pose a threat.
Let's deal with those who remained in Xue Yue first
and then we'll get rid of those who fled.
Let's take our time.
Senior Brother,
are there still no news from the country of Suzaku ?
It's been several years
since the Elders went to Suzaku.
How can there be no news at all !?
The technique to forcefully raise the cultivation of an individual
must not be easy to pull off.
Now that we have our new land,
to raise our country to rank 5
we need a cultivator to reach Soul Transformation.
There's no other way.
The empowerment ceremony is too risky !
Everyone only has one shot at it.
Even if one reaches Soul Transformation,
he will only have 100 years of lifespan
and will forever be stuck at Early stage
without being able to breakthrough !
I hope that among the Elders
at least one will be able to reach Soul Transformation.
That way, we will have 100 years
to solidify our position as rank 5.
It seems
that Xue Yue is governed locally by City Lords.
So their strength must vary from city to city.
11 floors ?
Who...
Sun Shouyi\N72nd Xue Yue City Lord\NLate stage Core Formation
Who are you ?
I need your identity.
How dare you !
I'm the City Lord !
Master.
Sun Shouyi's third disciple\NLate stage Foundation Establishment
Sun Shouyi's second disciple\NLate stage Foundation Establishment
According to this person's memory,
this girl often serves him personally.
Master...
I didn't expect that in Xue Yue,
a disciple serving his master would be so common.
Have any new ice embryos arrived ?
Master,
2 of them just arrived.
Bring them out
and let me see if your skills have improved.
Understood.
According to this person's memory,
the technique's first step
is to construct 9 blood veins in the ice embryo.
The next step
is to use the Icy Snow Tactic of Xue Yue to activate it.
Master...
You haven't answered my question from a few days ago
so disciple's cultivation is having problems.
Please come and instruct me tonight.
Speak,
what's the issue ?
Master...
Do we talk about it here ?
Master,
disciple was wrong !
I didn't think straight.
Continue.
Bones of ice,
soul of snow !
Disciple
failed again.
According to this person's memory,
the Icy Snow Tactic emphasizes refining the heart.
This technique uses ice as the bones and snow as the soul
to form an ice and snow soul
and reach the state of a clear heart.
It's very meticulous but unstable.
There is no room for error.
Senior Brother is back !
Disciple greets Master.
I have found the place
where remnants of the Four Sect Alliance are hiding.
How about
we call Zhao Li of the Ice Snow Palace
and ask them to send...
Lead the way.
Master,
it's right here.
I sense a restriction that's guarding 2 cultivators.
One is just a Core Formation.
The other one
oscillates between Core Formation
and Nascent Soul.
There are even hints of Soul Formation.
It looks like his cultivation is collapsing
and he's about to die.
You wait here.
Master never took risks himself before...
Chen Huan\NBlack Soul Sect Junior Sect Leader \NEarly stage Core Formation
Please don't kill my master,
kill me instead !
I'm the Junior Sect Leader of the Black Soul Sect.
If you capture me,
you will be rewarded.
Please spare my master.
Why do you want to exchange your life for your master's ?
If my master didn't have
to drag me around,
he would have left a long time ago.
But he tried to save me...
Huan'er,
get up.
This person is not a cultivator of Xue Yue.
Master...
you're awake !
Junior greets Senior of the Black Soul Sect.
This person is surronded by a death aura,
he's about to die.
He's beyond saving.
Little friend,
this old man's body is too injured
to greet you properly.
I hope you will forgive me.
Senior's hiding place
has been found by Xue Yue cultivators
so it's best to leave now.
I've lived in the Four Sects Alliance for more than 30 years.
But I couldn't help much
during the war with Xue Yue.
This time,
I will do my best to help.
Your injury is too serious
for this bottle of pills to heal, but it can ease the pain.
This should allow you to leave this place.
The world is big
so there might be other chances
to recover your cultivation.
Little friend,
I don't know what Sect you're from,
but if I wanted to leave,
I could have left back then.
Even if it means,
speeding up the loss of my cultivation.
I can still leave right now.
However,
do you know why I don't want to leave ?
This is my home.
I was born here
and when I die,
it will also be here.
Little friend,
this artifact is for you.
It's to thank you for the pills you've given me.
Thank you, Senior.
Huan'er,
it's time to go.
Master,
where are we going ?
I woke up today
like a candle before it's extinguished.
Go,
you will have to rely on yourself in the future
because Master can't protect you anymore.
No...
Master...
don't...
Master !
You bastards of Xue Yue...
Come here !
Even if I die today,
I will die
while protecting my country !
The fake Red Butterfly's sacrifice...
The fear of death of Xue Yue's mortals...
The generosity of this Senior towards me...
Master !!!
It turns out that Death
has many different meanings.
3 years later
Spring and autumn pass by,
snow falls as winter comes again.
My research on the ice sculptures
has made some progress.
The ice sculptures are maintained by the blood veins.
A sculpture with 49 blood veins
is able to achieve Core Formation level.
The more blood veins in the sculpture,
the stronger it is.
But if they collide with each other,
the sculpture will collapse.
This Icy Snow Tactic
cannot be considered correct.
It's definitely a branch of something else.
It's similar to the Six Desire Devil Lord's cultivation method.
Instead of snow blood,
these veins use pure blood.
This way I give it a bit of Life and Death Domain
to be able to control it.
4 years have passed.
It's time to leave.
In the war,
I've seen many deaths.
My feelings towards Death are still profound.
Master,
where are we going now ?
I will return to my roots.
But where is my home ?
I'm a year away from Soul Formation.
I was born in Zhao,
so I will return to Zhao.
That's the law of cause and effect.
“I, Chen Huan, swear that I’ll wipe out Xue Yue !”\NWang Lin returned to the ice tower with a complicated state of mind. Although he had obtained a powerful artifact, he didn’t feel happy. He only felt a sense of melancholy.\NAt this moment, Wang Lin suddenly gained another bit of insight of his Life and Death Domain.\N\N“What is Life… what is Death…”\N\NThis question echoed in Wang Lin’s mind.\NThe late stage Soul Formation cultivator of the Black Soul Sect used the last of his cultivation to fly up to the snow fairy statue at the Divine Temple of Snow and Ice. Like a moth flying toward a flame, he exploded on the statue, leaving behind a red mark that they couldn’t get rid of.\NAlong with him, several other Soul Formation cultivators were killed in this explosion.\NAll the glory was now gone with the wind…\NIn his death, he died at the right spot. His death awakened the Four Sect Alliance cultivators that hadn’t dared to show their faces.\N\NIn the blink of an eye, another year passed.\N\NThroughout this year, Wang Lin kept thinking about the Life and Death Domain, and he gradually gained more insight. His own being had undergone a transformation in this past year.\NLooking at a mountain as a mountain, looking at a river as a river.\NHowever, Wang Lin noticed that sometimes a mountain isn’t mountain and a river isn’t a river. It was as if there was another layer of fog blocking his eyes. He couldn’t see it, but he could feel it. When he reached out, he couldn’t touch it.\NThis type of thing won’t go away with time. He would need a sudden burst of insight to get past the fog.
I've had my share of wounds,
now I want to fight back.
Is my destiny a wall of restrictions
that's blocking all my hopes
for life ?
My flesh and blood witnessed the past,
my adversity pushed me to brave the waves.
How do you navigate through the years passing by ?
Nirvana and rebirth are no longer
out of reach.
Immortals
are obsessed with delusions of grandeur.
Renegades
seek to crush the impermanence of the heavens.
Don't tell me that I overestimate myself
and that the path to revenge leads to hell
because I don't see the harm in that.
My new body opens its eyes
and awakens from its dream.
I have overcome many trials
to get this body back.
No matter how many endless dark nights go by,
I can still see.
By sticking to this thought, I will get it done
by my own hands.
Returning to my body opened my eyes,
I need to continue my Immortal journey.
With a flick of a finger,
only my indomitable heart remains.
Life and death trials temper me, I am not afraid of losing my soul.
Even if there are countless tribulations and hardships.
Overcome this fate, smash through the obstacles,
like the descent of a god.